<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>3D Printing on The Electronic Press</title><link>https://pressers.name/categories/3d-printing/</link><description>Recent content in 3D Printing on The Electronic Press</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2015 15:46:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pressers.name/categories/3d-printing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Metalcasting by 3D Printer</title><link>https://pressers.name/2015/01/02/3d-printing-and-metalcasting/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2015 15:46:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pressers.name/2015/01/02/3d-printing-and-metalcasting/</guid><description>Starting at the End I used 3D printing to create a pendant for a friend. The steps I took are below. However, I&amp;rsquo;m so excited about the end product that I wanted to start by showing it off.
The Adventure Begins On a whim, I asked a friend to give me an idea for something to 3D print. She&amp;rsquo;s a huge fan of Garth Nix&amp;rsquo;s Abhorsen series and admires the Clayr.</description></item><item><title>New software - GCode splitter!</title><link>https://pressers.name/2014/03/07/new-software-gcode-splitter/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2014 02:00:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pressers.name/2014/03/07/new-software-gcode-splitter/</guid><description>Over the last few months, I&amp;rsquo;ve been silent as I transitioned from the life of a student to the life of a professional. But! I have finished that transition (for the most part) and am now back. I even bring new software with me.
This new software (which has the rather uncreative name &amp;ldquo;gcode splitter&amp;rdquo;) is a utility for use in 3D printing. I have acquired a 3D printer for me to experiment with.</description></item><item><title>Extruding Silhouettes for 3D Printing with Inkscape and OpenSCAD</title><link>https://pressers.name/2013/09/13/extruding-silhouettes-3d-printing-inkscape-and-openscad/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2013 23:54:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pressers.name/2013/09/13/extruding-silhouettes-3d-printing-inkscape-and-openscad/</guid><description>I recently found myself in a position where I wanted to extrude a logo so I could 3D print it. Unfortunately, this is a pretty difficult process to figure out without instructions. Therefore, I decided to document it. This process assumes you&amp;rsquo;re starting with a pixel-based image (bitmap, jpg, etc). If instead you have a vector graphic (SVG, etc) you should be able to do this by starting at the export step.</description></item><item><title>Defense Distributed, 3D Firearms and People Who Should Have Shut Up and Left It To The Pros. Oh my.</title><link>https://pressers.name/2013/05/08/defense-distributed-3d-firearms-and-people-who-should-have-shut-and-left-it-pros-oh-my/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2013 22:14:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pressers.name/2013/05/08/defense-distributed-3d-firearms-and-people-who-should-have-shut-and-left-it-pros-oh-my/</guid><description>Edit: Just before the publication of this article, Defense Distributed voluntarily removed the designs for the Liberator from their website, at the request of the Department of Defense. In my opinion, this is Defense Distributed getting the legal fight with the government it was spoiling for. More on that to follow.
Hello again world. How are you today? It&amp;rsquo;s been a while since I last posted, mostly due to school. Good news is that I had an awesome semester and worked on some very cool projects.</description></item></channel></rss>