<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Germany on The Electronic Press</title><link>https://pressers.name/categories/germany/</link><description>Recent content in Germany on The Electronic Press</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Nov 2021 10:38:14 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pressers.name/categories/germany/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Getting new lenses for Lensfun</title><link>https://pressers.name/2021/11/21/getting-new-lenses-lensfun-notes/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Nov 2021 10:38:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pressers.name/2021/11/21/getting-new-lenses-lensfun-notes/</guid><description>Since moving to Germany, I&amp;rsquo;ve started taking pictures. Lots here is beautiful, and my cell phone camera just didn&amp;rsquo;t seem to be cutting it. So I bought a camera &amp;ndash; a (used) Canon G5 X. The photos at the top and bottom of this post are a couple I&amp;rsquo;m proud of.
Of course, using a real camera means using real photo editing software. I run Linux on my laptop. Specifically, at the moment, Ubuntu.</description></item><item><title>Living in Germany: Converting a Driver's License</title><link>https://pressers.name/2021/10/04/living-germany-converting-drivers-license/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2021 15:28:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pressers.name/2021/10/04/living-germany-converting-drivers-license/</guid><description>I don&amp;rsquo;t ever plan to drive in Germany. The public transit here is amazing, and in 7 months of living here, I haven&amp;rsquo;t once wished I had a car. But there are some things one can&amp;rsquo;t do by public transit (like moving furniture or appliances). I will eventually have to do those and would like to have the flexibility to drive if needed. So I want to keep my ability to drive, which means converting my US license to a German one.</description></item><item><title>I'm moving to Germany!</title><link>https://pressers.name/2021/02/08/im-moving-germany/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2021 21:52:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pressers.name/2021/02/08/im-moving-germany/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m moving to Germany in March! I took a position as a researcher at HLRS (in Stuttgart, Germany), where I&amp;rsquo;ll be working primarily on SODALITE.
I&amp;rsquo;m really excited about this for a number of reasons. The largest is simply that I miss being in a research environment. I miss being around people thinking about big problems in a variety of ways, just for the fun of thinking about them. Over the last few years, I&amp;rsquo;ve published two papers, been issued a patent, and spoken at three conferences.</description></item></channel></rss>