<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>The Electronic Press</title><link>https://pressers.name/</link><description>Recent content on The Electronic Press</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pressers.name/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Enigma 2022</title><link>https://pressers.name/2022/02/01/enigma-2022/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pressers.name/2022/02/01/enigma-2022/</guid><description>I appeared at Enigma 2022 to give a talk called &amp;ldquo;Broken CAPTCHAs and Fractured Equity: Privacy and Security in hCaptcha&amp;rsquo;s Accessibility Workflow&amp;rdquo;. That talk came with a fair amount of accompanying material, including videos, slides, and code. That material can all be found on the Enigma 2022 page.
There will eventually be video.</description></item><item><title>Enigma 2022 Resources and Q&amp;A</title><link>https://pressers.name/enigma2022/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pressers.name/enigma2022/</guid><description>This page contains resources related to my February 2nd, 2022 talk, &amp;ldquo;Broken Captchas and Fractured Equity: Privacy and Security in hCaptcha&amp;rsquo;s Accessibility Workflow&amp;rdquo;. Each section of this page begins with a level 2 header.
Table of Contents Slides External Resources on Accessibility Technology and Software Accessibility Code Video Frequently Asked Questions Questions, Comments and Other Things Slides Download the slides as Open Office ODP or PowerPoint PPTX. These include speaker&amp;rsquo;s notes with approximately what I&amp;rsquo;ll say, transcripts and descriptions of the videos, and descriptions of all images used in the talk.</description></item><item><title>Getting new lenses for Lensfun</title><link>https://pressers.name/2021/11/21/getting-new-lenses-lensfun-notes/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Nov 2021 10:38:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pressers.name/2021/11/21/getting-new-lenses-lensfun-notes/</guid><description>Since moving to Germany, I&amp;rsquo;ve started taking pictures. Lots here is beautiful, and my cell phone camera just didn&amp;rsquo;t seem to be cutting it. So I bought a camera &amp;ndash; a (used) Canon G5 X. The photos at the top and bottom of this post are a couple I&amp;rsquo;m proud of.
Of course, using a real camera means using real photo editing software. I run Linux on my laptop. Specifically, at the moment, Ubuntu.</description></item><item><title>Living in Germany: Converting a Driver's License</title><link>https://pressers.name/2021/10/04/living-germany-converting-drivers-license/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2021 15:28:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pressers.name/2021/10/04/living-germany-converting-drivers-license/</guid><description>I don&amp;rsquo;t ever plan to drive in Germany. The public transit here is amazing, and in 7 months of living here, I haven&amp;rsquo;t once wished I had a car. But there are some things one can&amp;rsquo;t do by public transit (like moving furniture or appliances). I will eventually have to do those and would like to have the flexibility to drive if needed. So I want to keep my ability to drive, which means converting my US license to a German one.</description></item><item><title>I'm moving to Germany!</title><link>https://pressers.name/2021/02/08/im-moving-germany/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2021 21:52:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pressers.name/2021/02/08/im-moving-germany/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m moving to Germany in March! I took a position as a researcher at HLRS (in Stuttgart, Germany), where I&amp;rsquo;ll be working primarily on SODALITE.
I&amp;rsquo;m really excited about this for a number of reasons. The largest is simply that I miss being in a research environment. I miss being around people thinking about big problems in a variety of ways, just for the fun of thinking about them. Over the last few years, I&amp;rsquo;ve published two papers, been issued a patent, and spoken at three conferences.</description></item><item><title>I Finally Finished King's Quest 6!</title><link>https://pressers.name/2021/01/23/i-finally-finished-kings-quest-6/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2021 04:14:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pressers.name/2021/01/23/i-finally-finished-kings-quest-6/</guid><description>Well, tonight, I did it. I finished King&amp;rsquo;s Quest 6! A feat 25 years in the making, at least for me.
I used to play this game at my grandparents&amp;rsquo;, on my grandfather&amp;rsquo;s computer. We&amp;rsquo;d sit for hours just poking things on the screen. It was probably 1995, we were all between 3 and 7 years old and - in the manner of children - not so much actually trying to progress in the game so much as entertaining ourselves.</description></item><item><title>The Post of Shame</title><link>https://pressers.name/2021/01/02/post-shame/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 14:13:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pressers.name/2021/01/02/post-shame/</guid><description>So this site has been down since at least July 9, 2019 (according to my email). And the reasons were pretty simple &amp;ndash; and dumb. This post is going to be a sort of post-mortem on why it failed and what the fixes were. And (hopefully) it&amp;rsquo;ll include some lessons learned.
About the Site This site runs on apache2 on a debian-stable server. The underlying site is written in Django. The entire site is supposed to be self-maintaining.</description></item><item><title>Metalcasting by 3D Printer</title><link>https://pressers.name/2015/01/02/3d-printing-and-metalcasting/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2015 15:46:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pressers.name/2015/01/02/3d-printing-and-metalcasting/</guid><description>Starting at the End I used 3D printing to create a pendant for a friend. The steps I took are below. However, I&amp;rsquo;m so excited about the end product that I wanted to start by showing it off.
The Adventure Begins On a whim, I asked a friend to give me an idea for something to 3D print. She&amp;rsquo;s a huge fan of Garth Nix&amp;rsquo;s Abhorsen series and admires the Clayr.</description></item><item><title>Booting Gentoo from LVM in RAID</title><link>https://pressers.name/2014/09/11/booting-gentoo-lvm-raid/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2014 03:56:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pressers.name/2014/09/11/booting-gentoo-lvm-raid/</guid><description>I run Gentoo Linux on my personal servers, including my RAID server. (I have a dedicated server for raid and file dumps. What, you don&amp;rsquo;t?). When I first set this machine up 2-3 years ago, I gave it a single HDD (yes, spinning iron!) to boot from. At the time, my rationale was &amp;ldquo;hey, if it dies, the RAID is intact, I just have to rebuild the system&amp;rdquo;. Now, I&amp;rsquo;m changing from having several home directories scattered over all my machines to keeping a unified home directory in AFS.</description></item><item><title>The 9/11 Commission is Massively, Completely and Catastrophically Wrong</title><link>https://pressers.name/2014/09/02/911-commission-massively-completely-and-catastrophically-wrong/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2014 22:49:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pressers.name/2014/09/02/911-commission-massively-completely-and-catastrophically-wrong/</guid><description>Note from Steve (April 3, 2022): I&amp;rsquo;m leaving this up because it&amp;rsquo;s a thing I wrote once upon a time. In the intervening 7.5 years, some of my opinions have shifted. Some haven&amp;rsquo;t. And frankly I&amp;rsquo;m not sure about some of my textual interpretation here anymore. A post like this is best left to experts - not some 23-year-old.
I still think &amp;ldquo;hacking back&amp;rdquo; is a terrible idea, but we&amp;rsquo;ve managed not to have a cyberattack turn into a shooting war.</description></item><item><title>New software - GCode splitter!</title><link>https://pressers.name/2014/03/07/new-software-gcode-splitter/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2014 02:00:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pressers.name/2014/03/07/new-software-gcode-splitter/</guid><description>Over the last few months, I&amp;rsquo;ve been silent as I transitioned from the life of a student to the life of a professional. But! I have finished that transition (for the most part) and am now back. I even bring new software with me.
This new software (which has the rather uncreative name &amp;ldquo;gcode splitter&amp;rdquo;) is a utility for use in 3D printing. I have acquired a 3D printer for me to experiment with.</description></item><item><title>Extruding Silhouettes for 3D Printing with Inkscape and OpenSCAD</title><link>https://pressers.name/2013/09/13/extruding-silhouettes-3d-printing-inkscape-and-openscad/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2013 23:54:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pressers.name/2013/09/13/extruding-silhouettes-3d-printing-inkscape-and-openscad/</guid><description>I recently found myself in a position where I wanted to extrude a logo so I could 3D print it. Unfortunately, this is a pretty difficult process to figure out without instructions. Therefore, I decided to document it. This process assumes you&amp;rsquo;re starting with a pixel-based image (bitmap, jpg, etc). If instead you have a vector graphic (SVG, etc) you should be able to do this by starting at the export step.</description></item><item><title>Defense Distributed versus the US Government</title><link>https://pressers.name/2013/06/08/defense-distributed-versus-us-governemnt/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2013 14:42:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pressers.name/2013/06/08/defense-distributed-versus-us-governemnt/</guid><description>In my last entry, I mentioned that the United States Department of Defense had requested Defense Distributed remove the plans for their 3D printed firearm from the internet. I also mentioned that I believed this was Defense Distributed getting the legal fight it had been spoiling for.
Eating my Words However, I believe I have to eat my words. It has now been more than a month since the USDoD requested the plans be removed form the internet and there has been no response (other than compliance) from Defense Distributed.</description></item><item><title>Defense Distributed, 3D Firearms and People Who Should Have Shut Up and Left It To The Pros. Oh my.</title><link>https://pressers.name/2013/05/08/defense-distributed-3d-firearms-and-people-who-should-have-shut-and-left-it-pros-oh-my/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2013 22:14:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pressers.name/2013/05/08/defense-distributed-3d-firearms-and-people-who-should-have-shut-and-left-it-pros-oh-my/</guid><description>Edit: Just before the publication of this article, Defense Distributed voluntarily removed the designs for the Liberator from their website, at the request of the Department of Defense. In my opinion, this is Defense Distributed getting the legal fight with the government it was spoiling for. More on that to follow.
Hello again world. How are you today? It&amp;rsquo;s been a while since I last posted, mostly due to school. Good news is that I had an awesome semester and worked on some very cool projects.</description></item><item><title>Booting Windows in both a VM and Bare Metal</title><link>https://pressers.name/2013/01/07/booting-windows-both-vm-and-bare-metal/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2013 02:51:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pressers.name/2013/01/07/booting-windows-both-vm-and-bare-metal/</guid><description>So. My laptop primarily runs linux. However, I&amp;rsquo;ve got a few reasons to run Windows - gaming being one of them, watching streaming SilverLight video (choughnetflixcough) another. Rebooting a machine every time I want to switch operating systems is rather a drag. However, for some things (gaming), I&amp;rsquo;ll want to be doing this anyway. So I figured out how to make Windows both bare-metal boot and VM boot. I make no guarantees about any sort of performance.</description></item><item><title>Introducing Shrubbery: a cheap BMC-equivalent for Linux Machines</title><link>https://pressers.name/2013/01/06/introducing-shrubbery-cheap-bmc-equivalent-linux-machines/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2013 01:31:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pressers.name/2013/01/06/introducing-shrubbery-cheap-bmc-equivalent-linux-machines/</guid><description>I run a little server on my apartment network for small services (an IRC bouncer, some screens, SSH and MD-Raid). However, I&amp;rsquo;m not always at the machine when I&amp;rsquo;m working on it. I have, in the past, been lucky and not taken it totally offline when doing upgrades remotely. Until this week.
Having now accidentally removed myself from all the services I usually use, I&amp;rsquo;m frustrated. In my work life, I often use servers which have Baseboard Management Controllers (BMC).</description></item><item><title>Notes: Adding libGL.so to android emulator images</title><link>https://pressers.name/2012/12/22/notes-adding-libglso-android-emulator-images/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Dec 2012 05:04:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pressers.name/2012/12/22/notes-adding-libglso-android-emulator-images/</guid><description>Earlier this evening, I was playing with Android emulators. Specifically, I was playing with emulating an application which uses libGL. On emulator boot, I was getting messages like:
libGL.so: cannot open shared object file: No such file or directory It turns out that though no version of the binary is included in the default ADK, the correct one can simply be linked in. On my Debian Wheezy/testing machine, this was done as:</description></item><item><title>Building the ACM Cluster, Part 11g: OpenAFS RPM Build</title><link>https://pressers.name/2012/12/17/building-acm-cluster-part-11f-openafs-rpm-build/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2012 05:25:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pressers.name/2012/12/17/building-acm-cluster-part-11f-openafs-rpm-build/</guid><description>OpenAFS is the open source version of the AFS - a file system developed at Carnegie-Mellon University. AFS has a global, DNS-based address space. It also has a ton of nice features with respect to allowing users to create and control their own groups and much more granular permissions. All in all it seems to be a good way to get data into a cluster and to allow users to store and manage documents in a reliable format.</description></item><item><title>Building the ACM Cluster, part 11f: ZFS on Linux</title><link>https://pressers.name/2012/12/16/building-acm-cluster-part-11f-zfs-linux/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Dec 2012 23:59:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pressers.name/2012/12/16/building-acm-cluster-part-11f-zfs-linux/</guid><description>ZFS is one of those pieces of software that is almost frighteningly good at what it does. It has a whole slew of features that make it, for many uses, the perfect filesystem. These include: deduplication, compression, data integrity guarantees (ZFS can detect and repair silent data corruption), copy-on-write architecture and a built in concept of RAID. The only problem is that the source is under a license incompatible with the linux kernel, so it will never be kernel mainline.</description></item><item><title>Building the ACM Cluster, Part 11e: Building Ceph</title><link>https://pressers.name/2012/12/16/building-acm-cluster-part-11e-building-ceph/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Dec 2012 16:32:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pressers.name/2012/12/16/building-acm-cluster-part-11e-building-ceph/</guid><description>Ceph is a distributed storage engine. It can be used in a whole number of different ways - for example, as a block device or an object store. The current version is codenamed argonaut, hence the header image.
In the ACM cluster, we&amp;rsquo;re using it as the storage engine for VMs. This makes a lot of sense in our case, as the VMs are going to want to move from machine to machine and this stops them having to copy the disk image.</description></item><item><title>Building the ACM Cluster, Part 11d: Building Myricom fiber RPMs</title><link>https://pressers.name/2012/12/16/building-myricom-fiber-rpms/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Dec 2012 05:49:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pressers.name/2012/12/16/building-myricom-fiber-rpms/</guid><description>Welcome back to my ongoing series on building the JHUACM VM cluster. In this part, I&amp;rsquo;m going to be focusing on building the RPM driver for the Myricom fiber cards that were given to us with the cluster. Unfortunately the drivers for this are closed source. However, through my connections to physics, I was able to get source code to build from. In short, if you&amp;rsquo;re here looking for drivers, you&amp;rsquo;re out of luck - go talk to Myricom.</description></item><item><title>Building the ACM Cluster, Part 11c: Xen RPMs</title><link>https://pressers.name/2012/12/16/building-acm-cluster-part-11c-xen-rpms/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Dec 2012 04:24:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pressers.name/2012/12/16/building-acm-cluster-part-11c-xen-rpms/</guid><description>Next up, lets build RPMs of Xen, a hypervisor. Xen was chosen because on machines which do not have virtualization bits (like the cluster I&amp;rsquo;m building), Xen will do paravirtualization, which is still somewhat quick.Xen also has the concept of clustering and shifting VMs between instances - an important feature in a VM cluster!
Xen Spec Files CentOS 6 no longer has support for Xen. CentOS decided that they were going to put their weight behind QEMU/KVM as the virtulization solution and thus stopped distributing and supporting Xen.</description></item><item><title>Building the ACM Cluster, Part 11b: Kernel RPM Build</title><link>https://pressers.name/2012/12/16/building-acm-cluster-part-11b-kernel-rpm-build/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Dec 2012 04:11:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pressers.name/2012/12/16/building-acm-cluster-part-11b-kernel-rpm-build/</guid><description>If you haven&amp;rsquo;t already done so, read and execute Building the ACM Cluster, Part 11a: Setting up rpmbuild environment.
This article will be covering building a new kernel for CentOS and injecting it into xCat&amp;rsquo;s local package repository. I am covering this because later on we&amp;rsquo;ll need to have a more recent kernel than CentOS comes with by default. Xen specifically requires a later kernel. However, when we build kernel modules, we&amp;rsquo;ll want to be building against the same kernel version we&amp;rsquo;re running.</description></item><item><title>Building the ACM Cluster, Part 11a: Setting up rpmbuild environment</title><link>https://pressers.name/2012/12/15/building-acm-cluster-part-11a-setting-rpmbuild-environment/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Dec 2012 20:14:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pressers.name/2012/12/15/building-acm-cluster-part-11a-setting-rpmbuild-environment/</guid><description>Up to this point, we haven&amp;rsquo;t built any custom software for the cluster. I&amp;rsquo;ve tried very hard to use mostly off the shelf software. However, this has to change. Several of the major components we&amp;rsquo;re going to use (xen, the fiber card driver, ceph) are not available in the CentOS repositories (or are too old). So we&amp;rsquo;re going to build them ourselves.
However, rather than build them on a node-by node basis (which would make a single install hours long&amp;hellip;), we&amp;rsquo;re going to build packages.</description></item><item><title>Building the ACM VM Cluster, Part 10: Operating system image build</title><link>https://pressers.name/2012/12/15/building-acm-vm-cluster-part-8-operating-system-image-build/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Dec 2012 18:40:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pressers.name/2012/12/15/building-acm-vm-cluster-part-8-operating-system-image-build/</guid><description>Now that we&amp;rsquo;re done with network configuration. Now, lets actually build an operating system to use on the nodes!
Lets go ISO Huntin'! The first step in building operating system install images is to get the full operating system images. Not netboot, but a fully installable version. For CentOS the mirrors page is a good place to start your hunt. Personally, I downloaded both DVD images (CentOS-6.3-x86_64-bin-DVD1.iso and CentOS-6.3-x86_64-bin-DVD2.iso), though I suspect that simply the minimal image will cover it.</description></item><item><title>Building the ACM Cluster, Part 9: Setting up masquerade with iptables</title><link>https://pressers.name/2012/12/15/building-acm-cluster-part-8-setting-masquerade-iptables/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Dec 2012 18:22:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pressers.name/2012/12/15/building-acm-cluster-part-8-setting-masquerade-iptables/</guid><description>Alright! Lets get this started again. There is one last thing we need to do in order to have networking on the cluster functional. Right now, the nodes inside the cluster can&amp;rsquo;t speak to the outside world. While we set up the head node to be able to speak to things on every interface, we haven&amp;rsquo;t yet told it how to move traffic from one interface to another.
Making the Gateway In normal clusters, there are three types of notes - workers, gateways and head nodes.</description></item><item><title>End of the semester!</title><link>https://pressers.name/2012/12/15/end-semester/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Dec 2012 17:58:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pressers.name/2012/12/15/end-semester/</guid><description>Hey world! I&amp;rsquo;ve been inactive here the last month and a half because my semester got intense and I, frankly, didn&amp;rsquo;t have time. In this time, I&amp;rsquo;ve kept working on all my projects, job hunted and got hired. Phew. Busy time.
In any case, this is a &amp;ldquo;hello! still alive!&amp;rdquo; and a warning that you&amp;rsquo;re probably going to see me post quite a bit here over the next few days as I catch up on my backlog of documenting things.</description></item><item><title>ACM Talk: Version Control</title><link>https://pressers.name/2012/10/26/acm-talk-version-control/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Oct 2012 02:59:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pressers.name/2012/10/26/acm-talk-version-control/</guid><description>I gave a talk to JHUACM this evening about version control. Pretty basic stuff. Anyway, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d put a clearer link to my slides online in case it was useful for anyone.
Slides, PDF foramt
Slides, ODP format</description></item><item><title>Endeavor Time Lapse</title><link>https://pressers.name/2012/10/21/endeavor-time-lapse/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Oct 2012 00:19:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pressers.name/2012/10/21/endeavor-time-lapse/</guid><description>Hey everyone! It&amp;rsquo;s been a bit of a lazy weekend - I&amp;rsquo;ve mostly been doing schoolwork. I had some success with JHUACM cluster stuff that I haven&amp;rsquo;t written up yet (its fun! I rewrote the spec file for building RPMs of a proprietary driver!). However, I&amp;rsquo;ve come across a cool video to share.
Time Lapse: Endeavor&amp;rsquo;s Trip Through LA In case you missed it, the space shuttle Endeavor recently moved off to it&amp;rsquo;s new home in the California Science Center.</description></item><item><title>Building the ACM Cluster, Part 8: Adventures in Routing: Source Based (Multi-homed) Routing</title><link>https://pressers.name/2012/10/17/adventures-routing-source-based-multi-homed-routing/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2012 12:29:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pressers.name/2012/10/17/adventures-routing-source-based-multi-homed-routing/</guid><description>(This post is related to the ACM cluster build. However, it is really generic systems stuff and not terribly related to the actual cluster build. It is much more closely related to quirks of JHU networking.)
The Problem JHU has two distinct networks - firewalled and firewall-free. (In truth there are more and there are gradations, but these are the two JHUACM has IP allocations on.) Some services cannot be run form inside the firewalled network.</description></item><item><title>Building the ACM Cluster, Part 7: Network redux</title><link>https://pressers.name/2012/10/11/building-acm-cluster-part-7-network-redux/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Oct 2012 01:11:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pressers.name/2012/10/11/building-acm-cluster-part-7-network-redux/</guid><description>So I&amp;rsquo;ve mentioned that I&amp;rsquo;ve been fighting networking again in the ACM cluster. I&amp;rsquo;ve been reworking the network. This whole adventure began after a conversation with the very knowledgeable nwf, who pointed out that JHU runs two different networks that the ACM systems need access to - CSNet (the JHU Computer Science department&amp;rsquo;s network) and JHU firewall-free (which has unfiltered access to the internet). The goal of this rework was to allow the cluster to be on both.</description></item><item><title>Well, I disappeared...</title><link>https://pressers.name/2012/10/06/well-i-disappeared/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2012 11:49:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pressers.name/2012/10/06/well-i-disappeared/</guid><description>So. I&amp;rsquo;ve been quiet lately. I&amp;rsquo;m still working on everything I was before. But, the semester is in full swing, so I&amp;rsquo;ve had exams to study for. This weekend, however, is going to be mostly ACM stuff. A lot of that will be cleaning (I&amp;rsquo;ve made a mess with all the cluster gear lying about), but if I&amp;rsquo;m lucky, I&amp;rsquo;ll have a post early next week about the new network configuration for the ACM.</description></item><item><title>VoL - Voice over Light (link)</title><link>https://pressers.name/2012/09/22/vol-voice-over-light-link/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2012 20:08:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pressers.name/2012/09/22/vol-voice-over-light-link/</guid><description>Not much to say today - I&amp;rsquo;m busy working on a project for class (Its fun! Timers and sockets and protocols! (Oh my!)). However, a friend of mine posted a link on G+ I thought was really cool and wanted to share.
So without further ado: Throwing one&amp;rsquo;s voice 95 miles on a lightbeam - from KA7OEI.
As a techie and ham myself, I think this is really cool. It gets you into all sorts of things you don&amp;rsquo;t usually have to think about - earth&amp;rsquo;s geometry, atmospheric attenuation of light, and data encodings, to name a few.</description></item><item><title>Site Design</title><link>https://pressers.name/2012/09/18/site-design/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2012 00:05:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pressers.name/2012/09/18/site-design/</guid><description>Thanks to my very talented friend Kyle M., I now have a site design! I rather like it, but please do let me know if you find things that don&amp;rsquo;t render properly or any other issues.
And many many thanks to Kyle for producing something better than anything I could ever hope to make.</description></item><item><title>Configuring Cisco 2900XL Switches via TFTP (and alongside xCat)</title><link>https://pressers.name/2012/09/11/configuring-cisco-2900xl-switches-tftp-and-alongside-xcat/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2012 01:36:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pressers.name/2012/09/11/configuring-cisco-2900xl-switches-tftp-and-alongside-xcat/</guid><description>As part of my ACM cluster creation obsession, I wanted to make the Cisco 2900XL switches we have autoconfigure. I&amp;rsquo;m not terribly familiar with how these switches operate and, rather than reconfigure all of them at once, I&amp;rsquo;d much rather be able to reboot (reload, in cisco parlence) them and have them come up with my new, clean config.
Fortunately for me, Cisco thought of a situation like this when building the software for these switches.</description></item><item><title>Building the ACM Cluster, Part 6: Network Configuration</title><link>https://pressers.name/2012/09/09/building-acm-cluster-part-6-network-configuration/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2012 21:51:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pressers.name/2012/09/09/building-acm-cluster-part-6-network-configuration/</guid><description>In part 5 of this series, I covered the generic xCat setup and we told it how the network was set up. We&amp;rsquo;ve done little bits of network setup before (like setting our switches up for SNMP read access in the public community). Now we&amp;rsquo;re going to do quite a bit more.
Telling xCat where Nodes Are xCat has this wonderful ability to know what a newly plugged in machine is, based on where it is on a switch.</description></item><item><title>Building the ACM VM Cluster, Part 5: xCat configuration</title><link>https://pressers.name/2012/09/09/building-acm-vm-cluster-part-5-xcat-configuration/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2012 19:41:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pressers.name/2012/09/09/building-acm-vm-cluster-part-5-xcat-configuration/</guid><description>In part 4 of this series, we installed xCat. Now its time to configure it.
But First&amp;hellip; But first, lets talk a little about how you interact with xCat. xCat stores its configuration files in &amp;ldquo;tab&amp;quot;s - tables. In the default case, these are sqlite tables, though some will try to convince you to change it to MySQL. Unless you&amp;rsquo;re running thousands of nodes or continually hitting xCat, I see no point in this changeover and therefore will not cover it.</description></item><item><title>Building the ACM VM Cluster, Part 4: xCat Install</title><link>https://pressers.name/2012/09/09/building-acm-vm-cluster-part-4-xcat-install/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2012 13:19:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pressers.name/2012/09/09/building-acm-vm-cluster-part-4-xcat-install/</guid><description>In part 3 of this series, we got the management node set up to route traffic and generally properly configured. Now its time to actually install xCat!
Choices Many xCat guides recommend downloading the RPMs and manually installing those. The benefit of this route is that you need no network connection to your management node for this setup. However, I prefer to have a simple upgrade path. I also know my cluster will continuously be connected to the internet, so I don&amp;rsquo;t need an offline configuration.</description></item><item><title>Building the ACM VM Cluster, Part 3: Mangement Node Setup - Keepalived</title><link>https://pressers.name/2012/09/08/building-acm-vm-cluster-part-3-keepalived/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2012 21:45:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pressers.name/2012/09/08/building-acm-vm-cluster-part-3-keepalived/</guid><description>In part 2 of this series, I covered the network design - the last theoretical piece of design we need. Now let&amp;rsquo;s do some practical stuff! In this section I&amp;rsquo;m going to cover base network setup and keepalived installation on the management node.
Prerequisites For this I&amp;rsquo;ve assumed you already have a set up CentOS machine. In my case, its CentOS 6.3 (64-bit) though this may of course vary, in which case, refer to the XCat documentation to see any differences.</description></item><item><title>Building the ACM VM Cluster, Part 2: Network design</title><link>https://pressers.name/2012/09/08/building-acm-vm-cluster-part-2-network-design/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2012 21:04:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pressers.name/2012/09/08/building-acm-vm-cluster-part-2-network-design/</guid><description>Welcome to part 2 of my series of posts on building the ACM VM cluster! Part 1 covered the hardware and software that will be used in the cluster. Part 2 is going to focus on network design.
Introduction Typically in clusters there are two networks (usually represented by IP ranges, though sometimes actually physically separate): management and work. Management is typically mostly for master node to worker node communication (giving and getting work orders), whereas work is for intercommunication between nodes.</description></item><item><title>Building the ACM VM Cluster, Part 1: Hardware</title><link>https://pressers.name/2012/09/08/building-acm-vm-cluster-part-1/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2012 19:48:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pressers.name/2012/09/08/building-acm-vm-cluster-part-1/</guid><description>So I have a vision for the ACM systems - I&amp;rsquo;d like to make it so we are as redundant as possible and we can do updates to systems without having to take them offline. The obvious answer to this is using VMs, in a cluster. Fortunately, the ACM recently received a donation of the old DLMS cluster from physics (as well as three more recent Dell servers from JHU Housing and Dining).</description></item><item><title>Luna: A Case-Study in Failure</title><link>https://pressers.name/2012/09/08/luna-case-study-failure/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2012 17:23:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pressers.name/2012/09/08/luna-case-study-failure/</guid><description>I intended to make the first post here be about the technology under the site and how to set up a similar site. I will still write that one, but in the meantime a much more interesting problem has come up and I wish to share it with you.
This post is about the various issues, both human and machine that lead to the failure of Luna, the JHU ACM&amp;rsquo;s Xen virtual machine server.</description></item><item><title>Contact me</title><link>https://pressers.name/contact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pressers.name/contact/</guid><description>If you want to contact me, there are a few ways to do so.
The best is probably #span-7c9e393c.cloaked-e-mail:before { content:attr(data-domain) "\0040" attr(data-user); unicode-bidi:bidi-override; direction:rtl; } &amp;#32;&amp;#32; var scriptTag = document.getElementById("script-7c9e393c"); var link = document.createElement("a"); var address = "tcatnoc".split('').reverse().join('') + "@" + "eman.sresserp".split('').reverse().join(''); link.href = "mailto" + ":" + address; link.innerText = "by email"; scriptTag.parentElement.insertBefore(link, scriptTag.previousElementSibling); scriptTag.parentElement.removeChild(scriptTag.previousElementSibling) .
Of course, you could also reach out on:
Twitter LinkedIn</description></item></channel></rss>