<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Projects on The Electronic Press</title><link>https://pressers.name/categories/projects/</link><description>Recent content in Projects on The Electronic Press</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2014 03:56:50 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pressers.name/categories/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Booting Gentoo from LVM in RAID</title><link>https://pressers.name/2014/09/11/booting-gentoo-lvm-raid/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2014 03:56:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pressers.name/2014/09/11/booting-gentoo-lvm-raid/</guid><description>I run Gentoo Linux on my personal servers, including my RAID server. (I have a dedicated server for raid and file dumps. What, you don&amp;rsquo;t?). When I first set this machine up 2-3 years ago, I gave it a single HDD (yes, spinning iron!) to boot from. At the time, my rationale was &amp;ldquo;hey, if it dies, the RAID is intact, I just have to rebuild the system&amp;rdquo;. Now, I&amp;rsquo;m changing from having several home directories scattered over all my machines to keeping a unified home directory in AFS.</description></item><item><title>New software - GCode splitter!</title><link>https://pressers.name/2014/03/07/new-software-gcode-splitter/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2014 02:00:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pressers.name/2014/03/07/new-software-gcode-splitter/</guid><description>Over the last few months, I&amp;rsquo;ve been silent as I transitioned from the life of a student to the life of a professional. But! I have finished that transition (for the most part) and am now back. I even bring new software with me.
This new software (which has the rather uncreative name &amp;ldquo;gcode splitter&amp;rdquo;) is a utility for use in 3D printing. I have acquired a 3D printer for me to experiment with.</description></item><item><title>Introducing Shrubbery: a cheap BMC-equivalent for Linux Machines</title><link>https://pressers.name/2013/01/06/introducing-shrubbery-cheap-bmc-equivalent-linux-machines/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2013 01:31:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pressers.name/2013/01/06/introducing-shrubbery-cheap-bmc-equivalent-linux-machines/</guid><description>I run a little server on my apartment network for small services (an IRC bouncer, some screens, SSH and MD-Raid). However, I&amp;rsquo;m not always at the machine when I&amp;rsquo;m working on it. I have, in the past, been lucky and not taken it totally offline when doing upgrades remotely. Until this week.
Having now accidentally removed myself from all the services I usually use, I&amp;rsquo;m frustrated. In my work life, I often use servers which have Baseboard Management Controllers (BMC).</description></item></channel></rss>